

Fanie Reynders

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & SOLUTIONS **ARCHITECT**

http://reynders.co (http://reynders.co)

fanie@reynders.co (mailto:fanie@reynders.co)

★ Wethouder Hollaan 50 3984KD, Odijk, Utrecht, NL



(https://twitter.com/fanierevnders) (https://nl.linkedin.com/in/fanierevnders)





(https://www.facebook.com/faniereynders)



(https://github.com/faniereynders) (https://coderbits.com/faniereynders)

(https://channel9.msdn.com/Niners/FanieReynders)

(https://mvp.microsoft.com/en-us/PublicProfile/5001100)

(https://youtube.com/faniereynders)

For just over a decade, I've developed my passion for crafting software, focusing mostly on the Microsoft stack. I'm a dedicated and motivated Microsoft Certified Professional as well as a Microsoft Visual Studio and Development Technologies Most Valued Professional (MVP), who is focused on getting the job done the right way. I absolutely love creating software and try to push technology to its limits. In my free time I find myself constantly researching, blogging, tweeting, sharing knowledge and speaking at user groups & conferences.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Deloitte Digital

Senior Consultant Engineering

November 2016 to Present

https://www.deloittedigital.com (https://www.deloittedigital.com)

From digital evolution to revolution, from strategy to delivery, Deloitte Digital provides the capabilities to support organizations in the digital era. Part business, part creative, part technology, one hundred percent digital.

- Digital transformation of client's website and processes
- Mentoring multiple teams on latest technologies and standards
- · Modernization of current code base

- Stabilization and optimization of processes
- · Applied agile methodologies SCRUM

Fixx IT

Solutions Architect

June 2014 to October 2016

http://fixx.it (http://fixx.it)

Fixx IT is mainly a 'detachering' company focused on placing current employees at clients who can benefit from their skills and also builds in-house projects. One of the most recent projects is "Wheely Online": A powerful platform for searching & comparing cars in both the private and commercial sector, detailing transparent insights on how costs are calculated.

- Delivered a great Continuous Integration experience by verifying code with automated builds & tests
- Continuous Deployment across many environments
- Implemented cloud-ready infrastructure that can scale
- Produced LEAN software driven by plenty of POCs
- Followed agile methodologies, like SCRUM & Kanban
- Implemented on .NET Core, Microsoft's new cross platform framework

Rabobank (via Fixx IT)

Software Engineer / Consultant

March 2016 to October 2016

http://www.rabobank.nl (http://www.rabobank.nl)

Rabobank is one of the biggest banks in The Netherlands and consists of multiple cross functional teams. My role as Senior Developer played an influential role within one of the teams in the Investments sector and was responsible for mainly maintenance development which consisted of new features, stabilization and optimization of the current processes.

- · Code refactoring
- Stabilization and optimization of processes
- Code reviews
- Maintenance development

AgroVision (via Fixx IT)

Software Engineer / Consultant

June 2014 to December 2014

http://www.agrovision.nl (http://www.agrovision.nl)

AgroVision supplies specialised software for the international agricultural sector. Working specifically in the Crops division, my role as Senior Developer contributed to delivering high quality software used by their clients in the field. More information here: http://www.cropvision.nl

- Code reviews
- · Implemented integrations from external systems
- · Maintenance development

Dariel Solutions

Software Engineer / Consultant

February 2014 to April 2014

http://www.dariel.co.za (http://www.dariel.co.za)

Dariel Solutions is a proudly South African company focused on creating world-class bespoke software architecture, designed to solve their clients' specific needs. My role as Senior Developer helped the team develop a robust web-based portal for automating daily incoming policies for one of their clients. Read more on the use case here:

http://dariel.co.za/casestudy/leppard-underwriting-web-application

EOH Microsoft Services

Development Team Lead

March 2009 to January 2014

http://www.eohamp.co.za/ (http://www.eohamp.co.za/)

EOH Microsoft Services consists of a team of over 500 Microsoft Certified Professionals that understands the impact of your Microsoft Solutions on your organisation's bottom line.

- Assisted with daily code reviews
- Performed software audits for some of the clients
- Organized internal knowledge sharing sessions for mentoring fellow developers
- Responsible for research and development for a few projects
- · Research and apply best practices across teams

Momentum Outcome-based Solutions (via EOH)

Senior Software Engineer / Technical Lead

March 2009 to January 2014

http://www.momentuminv.co.za/MomentumOutcome-basedSolutions_Home/ (http://www.momentuminv.co.za/MomentumOutcome-basedSolutions_Home/)

Momentum Outcome-based Solutions (formerly Momentum Manager of Managers) was born from Advantage Asset Managers (Pty) Ltd, which was established on 1 January 2005 as a result of the merger of two prominent South African multi-managers, evolving from roots that extend as far back as 1994. My role as Technical Team Lead consisted of being a hands-on programmer within a team of 6 software developers who focused on delivering robust solutions to the client, not compromising on the quality of the solution. At the time the client was busy with migration projects from legacy systems.

- · Assited with dialy code reviews
- Involved with implementing best-practice architectures that are fit for purpose
- Mentoring of fellow developers
- Insuring on time delivery
- Facilitating system design workshops using requirements gathered from end-users.

Buphe Management

Software Engineer / Architect

December 2009 to December 2011

http://www.buphe.com/ (http://www.buphe.com/)

Founded in 2004 on the principles of affording top class healthcare to Africans, Buphe is committed to assisting Africans in the provision and access to better Healthcare. Buphe required a web-based back-office system for managing the administration around patient and treatment management. I consulted as Software Architect and implemented the initial version from the given requirements at the time.

- Automated & streamlined medical insurance applications
- · Making healthcare more accessible by using a web-based client
- Implemented overal architecture and design

Greatstock

Software Developer / Team Lead

March 2010 to August 2010

http://www.greatstock.co.za/ (http://www.greatstock.co.za/)

Greatstock has evolved from its early roots in producing award-winning cinema and TV commercials in the early eighties to become an integrated visual resource company. Their clients are mostly professionals in the advertising, marketing, design, production and publishing segments of local and international markets. My role consisted of being a developer focused on completing a search engine for photo and video footage as well as managing a small team focused on other projects in the company.

- Implemented integrations to streamline the import and digest of bulk images and film footage metadata
- Involved with the core design of the search and ranking engine
- Worked together with the designers to deliver a great user experience

Compu-Clearing

Software Developer

June 2007 to February 2009

http://www.compuclearing.za.com/ (http://www.compuclearing.za.com/)

Compu-Clearing is South Africa's industry leader in providing Information Technology products and services to Customs Clearing. During my time at Compu-Clearing I worked on numerous systems, mainly doing support and maintenance work. At a later stage I was tasked to create new web-based system to help with easily issuing air freight bills to their clients.

Cannibal Property Development

Software Developer

June 2005 to October 2005

Cannibal is a small real estate and property developer situated Western Johannesburg and required a system for use by their back office staff for managing monthly rental administration. My role as Software Developer was to develop & deliver this system within the requirements supplied.

C3 Specialists

Software Developer

June 2006 to April 2007

http://www.c3specialists.com.au/ (http://www.c3specialists.com.au/)

C3Specialists specialises in the design, analysis and investigation of Power & Industrial plant structures as well as Forensic engineering of all structural failures and defects and operate internationally. I was tasked to help build a module for interfacing with existing systems to help the engineer with analysis.



VOLUNTEER

Global Azure Bootcamp 2016

Speaker

April 2016 to April 2016

https://www.wazug.nl/Event/Details/2035 (https://www.wazug.nl/Event/Details/2035)

• Build intelligent bots with IoT on Azure

SDN Event

Speaker

April 2016 to April 2016

http://sdn.nl/ (http://sdn.nl/)

Lets build a bot - http://www.sdn.nl/EVENTS/8-april-2016

Global Azure Bootcamp 2015

Speaker

April 2015 to April 2015

http://sdn.nl/ (http://sdn.nl/)

Azure Mobile Services

SDN Event

Speaker

September 2015 to September 2015

http://sdn.nl/ (http://sdn.nl/)

A Lap around Chrome apps and extensions - http://www.sdn.nl/EVENTS/11-september-2015

Fixxup Developer User Group

Organizer & Speaker

January 2014 to Present

http://fixxup.nl/ (http://fixxup.nl/)

Fixxup is an initative started to bring good developers together for awesome knowledge sharing sessions to make them even better. These informative evenings is hosted and organized by me as a token to give back to the community.

- Modernize your backend with Azure API Management http://2015.fixxup.nl/events/modernize-your-backend-withazure-api-management
- A lap around Chrome apps and extensions http://2015.fixxup.nl/events/a-lap-around-chrome-apps-and-extensions
- .NET 2015: The next generation open ecosystem http://2015.fixxup.nl/events/net-2015-the-next-generation-openecosystem
- Exploring Azure App Service http://2015.fixxup.nl/events/exploring-azure-app-service
- MVC in ASP.NET Core: The new kid on the block http://fixxup.nl/blog/mvc-in-aspnet-core

OSS Project - Expando

Open source contribution

January 2014 to Present

https://atom.io/packages/expando-atom (https://atom.io/packages/expando-atom)

Expando generates instant data snippets for the Atom editor

OSS Project - WebApiProxy

Open source contribution

January 2012 to Present

https://github.com/faniereynders/WebApiProxy (https://github.com/faniereynders/WebApiProxy)

WebApiProxy is one of my hobby projects specifically designed for ASP.NET Web APIs. Unlike WCF with SOAP, RESTful services don't have the luxury of metadata for simply just adding a service reference. WebApiProxy solves this problem by extending your existing WebAPI with an additional endpoint for serving metadata which describes your service. Out of the box it comes with a server managed JavaScript client library as well as a handy C# generator to generate strongly-typed client libraries upon build or on demand.

MasterDev

Organizer & Judge

January 2011 to December 2012

MasterDev is a spin off from the famous cooking competition "Master Chef", but for developers. At each session contestants are divided into random groups and compete against each other to win a range of prizes sponsored by Microsoft and Nokia.



EDUCATION

Bytes People Solutions

BizTalk

Certification

March 2008 to March 2008

Managing & Deploying BizTalk

Microsoft

Microsoft Certified Professional

Certification

January 2012 to March 2013

- D969-1917 MCTS: .NET Framework 4, Web Applications
- E195-1139 MCTS: .NET Framework 4, Data Access
- E190-1659 MCTS: .NET Framework 4, Service Communication Applications
- E206-8592 MCPD: Web Developer 4

Tshwane University of Technology

Information Technology: Software Development

Diploma (3 years of HBO)

January 2004 to November 2006

Ben Vorster Highschool

National Senior Certificate (HAVO)

January 2002 to December 2003

Breinlyn Private School

January 1999 to December 2001



AWARDS

Microsoft .NET MVP 2015

Microsoft

2015-10-01

This award is given to exceptional technical community leaders who actively share their high quality, real world expertise with others. The Microsoft MVP Award provides us the unique opportunity to celebrate and honour your significant contributions.

Microsoft C# MVP 2014

Microsoft

2014-10-01

For more than two decades, Microsoft has recognized exceptional, independent community leaders who share their passion, technical expertise, and real-world knowledge of Microsoft products with others. It is part of Microsoft's commitment to supporting and enriching technical communities.



PUBLICATIONS

SDN Magazine 128 - Docfx helps us make documentation easier for .NET

SDN

2016-03-21

Link (http://sdn.nl/MAGAZINE/ID/1175/SDN-Magazine-128)

Write-up on a documentation generator for .NET called Docfx

SDN Magazine 128 - Migrate a .csproj from package.config to project.json

SDN

2016-03-21

Link (http://sdn.nl/MAGAZINE/ID/1175/SDN-Magazine-128)

A quick tutorial on how to migrate from Nuget 2 to 3 package systems.

SDN Magazine 126 - Exploring Azure App Service

SDN

2015-05-21

Link (http://sdn.nl/MAGAZINE/ID/132/SDN-Magazine-125)

An overview of Azure App Service

RESTful Services with ASP.NET Web API

Packt Publishing

2014-02-26

Link (http://www.packtpub.com/restful-services-with-aspnet-web-api/video)

Today, apps are everywhere, and most of these apps run on complex cloud-based back-ends. ASP.NET Web API allows you to easily create and deploy Web APIs to be consumed in a RESTful manner by developers to build rich and interactive applications. This video course is a great starting point for any web developer who wants to create simple web APIs in minutes. By applying your knowledge of ASP.NET in conjunction with the information provided in this video tutorial, you will learn to master the art of building RESTful services by example.

DNC Magazine: Remember you Hot Towel when going to the SPA

DNC Magazine

Link (http://www.dotnetcurry.com/magazine/dnc-magazine-issue6.aspx)

Using the Hot Towel template in your Single Page Apps.

%

SKILLS

Web Development Cloud (Azure)

Senior

- HTML5
- CSS 3
- JavaScript
- ASP.NET Core
- ASP.NET
- WebForms
- SignalR
- MVC
- Razor
- Tag Helpers
- Single Page Applications
- AngularJs
- KnockoutJs
- lonic
- JQuery
- JQuery Mobile
- TypeScript
- Bootstrap
- WCF
- Web Services

Senior

- Web Apps
- Mobile Apps
- Logic Apps
- API Apps
- API Management
- Cloud Services
- Application Insights
- Cognative Services
- Microsoft Bot Framework
- Notification Hubs
- Power BI
- Kudu
- Search Services
- loT Hubs
- Event Hubs
- BLOB Storage
- Queue Storage
- File Storage
- VMs
- Active Directory
- Azure SQL
- Schedulers
- Web Jobs
- Team Projects

Design & Architectual

Intermediate

- Unit of Work
- Repository Pattern
- Service Locator Pattern
- · Dependency Injection
- Inversion of Control
- Object Oriented Design
- Ninject
- Unity
- MEF
- Castle Windsor
- Domain Driven Design
- Decorator Pattern

Data Frameworks & Technologies

Intermediate

- SQL
- · Entity Framework
- Entity Modelling
- T-SQL

Other platforms & Languages

Senior

- .NET
- .NET Core
- C#
- VB.NET
- F#
- Windows Workflow Foundation
- Visual Studio
- LINQ
- Roslyn

Application Life Cycle

Senior

- SCRUM
- Agile
- Visual Studio Team Services
- Continuous Integration
- Continuous Delivery
- TFS
- Git



LANGUAGES

Afrikaans

Native

English

Professional working proficiency

Dutch

Professional working proficiency



INTERESTS

Family & Social

Internet of Things

Community